Guide to the Maynard Mack Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Alexander Pope Research and Writing, circa 1936-1993; Series III; 36.1; (74 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
  - Dariquenave, Charles (1664-1739), undated (Box 31)
  - Dennis, John, undated (Box 31)
  - Desaulnais, Charles (Duke Disney), undated (Box 31)
  - Digby Family, 1975-1979 (Box 31)
  - Disney, Henry, undated (Box 31)
  - Dodington, George, undated (Box 31)
  - Dodsley, Robert, undated (Box 31)
  - Douglas, Charles and Catherine (Queensbury), undated (Box 31)
  - Douglas, James, undated (Box 31)
  - Duck, Stephen, 1977 (Box 31)
  - Eckersall, James, 1975 (Box 31)
  - Englefields, Henry, 1957 (Box 31)
  - Fenton, Elijah, undated (Box 31)
  - Fermor Family, undated (Box 31)
  - Fielding, William (and wife), undated (Box 31)
  - Finch, Anne, undated (Box 31)
  - Floyd, Bridget, 1974 (Box 31)
  - Fortescue, William, 1971 (Box 31)
  - Foster, James, undated (Box 31)
  - Fox, Henry, undated (Box 31)
  - Garth, Samuel, 1979 (Box 31)
  - Shepherd's Week, 1976-1989 (Box 31)
  - Gay, John, undated (Box 31)
  - King George I, undated (Box 31)
  - Queen Caroline, undated (Box 31)
  - King George II, undated (Box 31)
  - Gerard, Elizabeth, 1974 (Box 31)
  - Germain, Elizabeth, undated (Box 31)
  - Godolphin, Sidney, undated (Box 31)
  - Granville, George, 1973 (Box 31)
  - Hales, Rev. Stephen, undated (Box 32)
  - Harcourt, Simon, 1993 (Box 32)
  - Harley, Edward, undated (Box 32)
  - Essay on Edward Harley, undated (Box 32)
  - Harley, Robert, undated (Box 32)
  - Hanbury - Williams, Charles, undated (Box 32)
  - Harte, William, undated (Box 32)
  - Hervey, John, 1978 (Box 32)
  - Hill, Aaron, undated (Box 32)
  - Hoadly, Benjamin, undated (Box 32)
  - Hooke, Nathaniel, undated (Box 32)
  - Howard, Henrietta, undated (Box 32)
  - Howard, Mary (Countess of Delloraine), undated (Box 32)
  - Howe, John, undated (Box 32)
  - Hughes, John, 1976 (Box 32)
  - Hume, Hugh (Marchmont, Third Earl), 1971 (Box 32)
  - Jervas, Charles, undated (Box 32)
  - Johnson, Samuel, undated (Box 32)
  - Kent, William, undated (Box 32)
  - King William, undated (Box 32)
  - Kneller, Godfrey, 1977 (Box 32)
  - Knight, John, undated (Box 32)
  - Lee, George Henry, undated (Box 32)
  - Lepell, Mary (Lady Hervey), undated (Box 32)
  - Lewis, Erasmus, undated (Box 32)
  - Lisle, Edward, undated (Box 32)
  - Lintot, Bernard, undated (Box 32)
  - Lumley, Richard (First Earl of Scarborough), undated (Box 32)
  - Mallet, David, 1979 (Box 33)
  - Mandeville, 1970 (Box 33)
  - Manley, Mary de la Riviera, undated (Box 33)
  - Mead, Richard, undated (Box 33)
  - Methuen, Paul, undated (Box 33)
  - Montagu, Charles, undated (Box 33)
  - Montagu, Mary Wortley, undated (Box 33)
  - Mordaunt, Charles, undated (Box 33)
  - Morice, William, undated (Box 33)
  - Moyser, John, undated (Box 33)
  - Nugent, Robert, undated (Box 33)
  - Oldmixon, John, undated (Box 33)
  - Parnell, Thomas, 1982-1987 (Box 33)
  - Pelham, Henry (Duke of Newcastle), undated (Box 33)
  - Pellett, Thomas, undated (Box 33)
  - Philips, Ambrose, undated (Box 33)
  - Pigott, Nathaniel, undated (Box 33)
  - Pitt family - Thomas and William, undated (Box 33)
  - Prior, M., undated (Box 33)
  - Rich, Christopher, undated (Box 33)
  - Richardson, Jonathan, 1988 (Box 33)
  - Rowe, Nicholas, undated (Box 33)
  - Rowe, N., undated (Box 33)
  - Russell, John (Duke of Bedford), undated (Box 33)
  - Savage, Richard, 1973 (Box 34)
  - Serle, John and wife, 1986 (Box 34)
  - Selwyn, George, undated (Box 34)
  - Sheffield, John, 1982 (Box 34)
  - Shirley, Lady Frances, undated (Box 34)
  - Smythe, James Moore (1702-1734), undated (Box 34)
  - Southcote, Thomas, 1960 (Box 34)
  - Spence, undated (Box 34)
  - Steele, Richard, 1972 (Box 34)
  - Spence, Joseph, undated (Box 34)
  - Stonor, Thomas, 1976 (Box 34)
  - Swift: Death of Dr. Swift, 1988 (Box 34)
  - Talbot, Charles, undated (Box 34)
  - Temple, Richard, undated (Box 34)
  - Tickell, undated (Box 34)
  - Temple, Richard: Viscount Cobham of Stowe, undated (Box 34)
  - Tonson, Jacob, undated (Box 34)
  - Townshend, Charles (2nd Viscount T.), undated (Box 34)
  - Trumbull, Sir William, 1977 (Box 34)
  - Vanbrugh, Sir John (1664-1726), undated (Box 34)
  - Voltaire, 1978 (Box 34)
  - Manuscript (?) (Box 34)
  - Walsh, William, undated (Box 35)
  - Warburton, William, undated (Box 35)
  - Walter, Peter, undated (Box 35)
  - Warton, Joseph, undated (Box 35)
  - Welsted, Leonard, undated (Box 35)
  - West, Gilbert, undated (Box 35)
  - Williams, Sir Charles, undated (Box 35)
  - Wycherley, William, undated (Box 35)
  - Wyndham, William, undated (Box 35)
  - Yorke, Philip (1st Earl of Hardwicke), undated (Box 35)
  - Richard Williams' Letters, undated (Box 35)
  - Pope's Books (Box 35)
    - AP: Presentation Copies, undated; 2 (Box 35)
  - Pope's Books (Box 35)
    - Pope and Montaigne, undated (Box 35)
    - Possible Papers on AP, undated (Box 35)
  - MB [Michael Blount]: Documents (facsimilies), undated (Box 36)
  - TB: Documents, undated (Box 36)
  - Mapledurham Manor: Dissertation on This is All That Concerns my Blounts, undated (Box 36)
  - Lister Blount and His Wife and His Will, undated (Box 36)
  - Mapledurham House, undated (Box 36)
  - MB's Expense Book 1744 and on, undated (Box 36)
  - Blount MSS, 1970-1972 (Box 36)
  - Poems in Blount MSS by Various Hands: MB's Collection, undated (Box 36)
  - AP and MB Marriage Question TB 40 Covenant, undated (Box 36)
  - MB: Letters and Personality, undated (Box 36)
  - Handcopied and duplicated letters, undated; 2 (Box 36)
  - MB to Schrader, undated (Box 37)
  - Alexis and Typographate Letters, undated (Box 37)
  - Blount mss: Scrader Letters, undated (Box 37)
  - Blounts: Rate Books, undated (Box 37)
  - Blount Will: Partial Indexes, undated (Box 37)
  - Mapledurham Library Catalogue, 1975 (Box 38)
  - Blount Genealogue, undated (Box 38)
  - G and C: Early Notes, undated (Box 39)
  - MSS: Lecture, undated (Box 39)
  - Correspondence Lecture III, undated (Box 39)
  - Northcliff 3: Appendix B AP Letters: A - E, 1975 (Box 39)
  - Northcliff 3: Appendix B, F - O, 1975 (Box 39)
  - Northcliff 3: Appendix B, P - T, 1975 (Box 39)
  - Northcliff 3: Appendix B Letters Xerox Copies, undated (Box 40)
  - Duplicates and typescripts of letters, undated; 2 (Box 40)
  - Personality: Lectures, undated (Box 41)
  - For Research Assistance (Box 41)
    - Researches to be Undertaken to her Deborah Knuth to AB, 1984 (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous Papers (1) Trelawny, (2) Harcondt, (3) Warton, (4) Edward Blount, 1971 (Box 41)
  - R.J. Goulden: Research, 1982 (Box 41)
  - For England, 1960-1965 (Box 41)
  - Beinecke Research (Box 41)
    - For Beinecke Investigation, undated (Box 41)
    - Academic and research correspondence, 1976 (Box 41)
  - Jonson, 1979 April (Box 42)
  - AP: Research, AB, 1978 (Box 42)
  - AB: documents, undated (Box 42)
  - MM: Pope Queries, Correspondence (Box 42)
    - Correspondence about Pope, undated (Box 42)
  - Hardwick Papers [empty], undated (Box 42)
  - Broome Papers, 1974 (Box 42)
  - Southcote Papers, undated (Box 42)
  - Diplomatic Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 42)
  - Denbigh Papers, 1970 (Box 42)
  - Digby Papers, undated (Box 42)
  - Cornbury Papers, 1973 (Box 42)
  - Stonor MSS, 1970 (Box 42)
  - Embassy Papers: Hague and Paris, 1964 (Box 42)
  - Pope's Tune: Essay to be Written on This and Style, undated (Box 42)
  - U.S. Research Outside Yale (Box 42)
  - Reviews of TE Homer, 1968-1969 (Box 42)
  - TE, Essay on Man, 1947-1951 (Box 42)
  - Essay on Man, Revisions for 2nd Edition, 1957 (Box 42)
  - On Reading Pope: Columbia, undated (Box 42)
  - Pope Biography: Y.G.Y. Morton [empty], undated (Box 42)
  - Norton's Pope Biography, undated (Box 42)
  - Life of Pope: U.S. Reviews, 1986-1987 (Box 43)
  - Printed articles, 1986 (Box 43)
  - Life of Pope: British Reviews, 1985-1990 (Box 43)
  - Life of Pope: European Reviews, 1985-1988 (Box 43)
  - AP, 1987-1988 (Box 43)
  - Plates for Biography, undated (Box 44)
  - Plates
    - Plates for Biography, undated (Box 44)
    - Thesis: That AP Portraits Show Classical and Modern Pope, 1986 (Box 44)
    - Biography: Permissions, undated (Box 44)
  - Plates
    - NPG and Courtauld Lists in London, 1984 (Box 44)
    - M.M.: Portrait of AP by JR; Entire Conservation Record by Andrew Petrogn, undated (Box 44)
  - Pope Biography: Yale side, 1986 (Box 44)
  - Prologue and Summing Up
    - AP Biography: Prologue, undated (Box 44)
    - MM: Summary on AP, undated (Box 44)
    - Suggestions from various people, 1983 (Box 44)
  - Biography as Book: Epigraphs, etc.
    - Pope Bio: Things to Get Done, undated (Box 45)
    - Pope: Sherburn Card File, undated (Box 45)
    - Copies to be Given, undated (Box 45)
    - AP Biography: Acknowledgements, undated (Box 45)
    - Biography as a Book: Epigraphs, Titles, Etc., undated (Box 45)
    - Eyston Contract, undated (Box 45)
  - AP Biography: General Mss. Sources (Box 45)
    - Earlier Biographies, 1975 (Box 45)
    - Other Biographies of Pope, undated (Box 45)
    - Biography Theory (Box 45)
  - AP Domiciles in London 1709-1714
    - AP Travels to Friends and Their Houses, undated (Box 45)
    - 18th c. Travel, undated (Box 45)
    - AP whereabouts 1704-1744, undated (Box 45)
  - Pope: Bibliographical
    - Pope: Bibliographical, 1967-1989 (Box 45)
  - Pope's Printers (Box 46)
    - Pope as Publisher, undated (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous research information, undated (Box 46)
  - Backgrounds: Ideological and Cultural
    - Article on Sir Isaac Newton, undated (Box 46)
    - Religion, undated (Box 46)
  - Backgrounds: Economic
    - Pope: Finances, undated (Box 46)
  - Backgrounds: Political
    - Lois Morrison Collection, undated (Box 46)
  - Backgrounds: Social
    - Social Backgrounds to the Poetry: smuggling, blacks, surgeons, political corruption, 1974 (Box 46)
    - Literature and the Other Arts, 1961 (Box 46)
    - 18th c. Entertainments, undated (Box 46)
  - Personal: Opinions of Men (Box 47)
  - Personal: Opinions of Books (Box 47)
  - AP as Letter Writer, undated (Box 47)
  - Personal: Governing Attitudes and Ideas
    - Recurrent or Governing Images, undated (Box 47)
    - Friendship, undated (Box 47)
  - Personal: Appearance and Characteristics
    - AP: Kindnesses, undated (Box 47)
    - The Physical Affliction, undated (Box 47)
  - Satire: Theory and Conventions
    - Pope Reading to Do, 1971-1978 (Box 48)
  - Ch I: 1688-1700
    - AP biography: Completed Portions, undated (Box 48)
  - Biography II: Text and Notes, undated (Box 48)
  - Roman Catholicism: the Outsider
    - AP's relations with Catholocism, undated (Box 48)
  - Backgrounds: Current Events 1688-1700, undated (Box 48)
  - Birth and Collateral Events 1688-1700
    - Pope, Alexander, Sr., undated (Box 49)
    - AP: His Father, 1994 (Box 49)
    - AP: His Mother, 1975-1986 (Box 49)
    - Bodby mss: Pope's Statement to JR, jr. Mrs. Rachett's [?], 1971 (Box 49)
    - AP Biography: Outline and Contents for Ch. I, undated (Box 49)
    - Dorothy Pope's Will, 1978 (Box 49)
  - Plough Court 1688-1700, 1984 (Box 49)
  - London records office papers and photos, undated (Box 49)
  - Contemporary London and its Life 1688-1700
    - Everyday Life in London, 1979 (Box 49)
    - Hammersmith, 1988 (Box 49)
  - Schools and Education 1688-1700, undated (Box 50)
  - Contemporary Events 1701-1709, undated (Box 50)
  - Binfield 1688-1700
    - AP: Binfield House, 1970-1977 (Box 50)
  - Life in the Forest 1701-1709, undated (Box 50)
  - Early Friends 1701-1709
    - AP Biography: Early Miscellaneous Friends, undated (Box 50)
  - Health 1701-1709 (empty), undated (Box 50)
  - Early Readings 1701-1709, 1976 (Box 50)
  - AP Library: (1) by Date of Acquisition (2) With Prices, 1977 (Box 50)
  - Early Writings 1701-1709, 1970 (Box 50)
  - Contemporary Events (Death of Anne 1714; Coronation of George I) 1709-1714, undated
    - Contemporary Events 1709, undated (Box 50)
    - Contemporary Events 1710, undated (Box 50)
    - Contemporary Events 1711, undated (Box 50)
    - Contemporary Events 1712, undated (Box 50)
    - Contemporary Events 1713, undated (Box 50)
    - Contemporary Events 1714, undated (Box 50)
    - Contemporary Events 1715, undated (Box 50)
  - Health 1709-1714 (empty), undated (Box 51)
  - The Blount Sisters 1709-1714 (empty), undated (Box 51)
  - Lady Mary 1709-1714, undated (Box 51)
  - Publications 1709
    - Georgics, undated (Box 51)
    - Pope and Pastoral, 1980 (Box 51)
  - Publications (empty), undated (Box 51)
  - Publications: Messiah 1712, undated (Box 51)
  - Publications: Sappho to Phaon 1712, undated (Box 51)
  - Publications: Statius 1712 (empty), undated (Box 51)
  - Publications: Arrival of Odysseus in Ithaca 1713, undated (Box 51)
  - Publications: Two-Canto Rape 1712 (empty), undated (Box 51)
  - Miscellaneous Publications 1709-1714 (empty), undated (Box 51)
  - Publications: Sarpedon: Homer 1709 (empty), undated (Box 51)
  - Publications: January and May, Chaucer 1709 (empty), undated (Box 51)
  - Publications, Pastorals: Virgil and Others 1709, 1979 (Box 51)
  - Publications: Essay on Criticism 1711
    - AP: Versification in General, 1950-1965 (Box 51)
  - Publications: Acis and Galatea 1749 (empty), undated (Box 51)
  - Publications: Vertunnus and Pomona 1712 (empty), undated (Box 51)
  - Publications: Windsor Forest 1713, undated (Box 52)
  - Mythologizing England, 1974 (Box 52)
  - Windsor Forest, 1973 (Box 52)
  - Publications: Wife of Bath's Prologue 1714 (empty), undated (Box 52)
  - Publications: Five-Canto Rape 1714
    - Additions for Rape of Lock, 1974-1977 (Box 52)
  - Notebook containing notes on Various People in Alphabetical Order, undated; 2 (Box 53)
  - Pope, Own Works: Presented, undated (Box 53)
  - Chapter 6: 1720-1730
    - Country House, 1972 (Box 53)
  - Contemporary Events 1715-1720: the 1715; Marlborough's Funeral 1717; Death of Addison 1719, undated (Box 53)
  - 1715-1720 (empty), undated (Box 54)
  - Removal to Chiswick 1716: 1715-1720, 1981 (Box 54)
  - Health 1715-1720 (empty), undated (Box 54)
  - In Love 1715-1720 (empty), undated (Box 54)
  - Removal to Twickenham 1718-1719: 1715-1720, 1989 (Box 54)
  - Friends 1715-1720 (empty), undated (Box 54)
  - Early Enemies (empty), undated (Box 54)
  - Enemies 1715-1720, undated (Box 54)
  - Publications 1715-1720, 1965-1967 (Box 54)
  - 1715: Temple of Fame (written 1711-1712) Publications (Box 54)
    - Temple of Fame, undated (Box 54)
  - Publications: 1715 Homer I, 1989 (Box 54)
  - Felicity Rosslyn's Dissertation, 1979 (Box 54)
  - Publications: 1716 Homer II (empty), undated (Box 54)
  - Publications: 1717 Homer III (empty), undated (Box 54)
  - Publications: 1718 Iliad IV (empty), undated (Box 54)
  - Publications: 1720 Iliad V-VI (empty), undated (Box 54)
  - Mme. Dacier on AP Iliad Preface London 1724 (empty), undated (Box 54)
  - Iliad 12 and Odyssey 7 in Photographs and Transcripts; also fragments of Iliad 8 and 16, undated (Box 54)
  - Publications: Three Hours After Marriage, undated (Box 55)
  - Works. Vol. 1, Preface. Publications
    - 1717 Preface, 1977 (Box 55)
  - Publications: Eloise to Abelard
    - Eloisa, 1967 (Box 55)
  - Publications: Unfortunate Lady, 1976 (Box 55)
  - Contemporary Events 1721-1726
    - Berkshire Blacks, 1973 (Box 55)
    - Atterbury Trial, undated (Box 55)
    - Pope MSS: Atterbury Letters, undated (Box 55)
  - Friends 1721-1726
    - Morley, John, undated (Box 55)
  - Enemies: Theobald 1721-1726
    - Theobald, Lewis, undated (Box 55)
  - Gardening 1721-1726, 1981 (Box 56)
  - Untitled folder, 1985 (Box 56)
  - Grottoing 1721-1726, 1989 (Box 56)
  - Health 1721-1726 (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - Building 1721-1726 (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - Publications 1721-1726, undated (Box 56)
  - 1721 Epistle to Addison, Publications (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - 1721 Epistle to Oxford, Publications (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - 1723 Edition of John Sheffield, Publications, 1989 (Box 56)
  - 1725 Edition of Shakespeare, 1970-1978 (Box 56)
  - 1725 Odyssey, Vols. I-III, Publications (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - 1726 Odyssey, Vols. IV-V, Publications, 1972-1986 (Box 56)
  - 1727-1730 (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - Contemporary Events: 1727-1730 Swift's Second Visit, undated (Box 56)
  - AB Notebook 1721-1730, undated (Box 56)
  - Health 1727-1730 (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - Enemies 1727-1730 (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - House 1727-1730 (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - Garden and Grotto 1727-1730 (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - Publications, undated (Box 56)
  - 1727: Pope-Swift Miscellaneous I-III, Publication (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - 1728: Pope-Swift Miscellaneous Publications "Last Volume" (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - 1728 Art of Sinking, Publications, undated (Box 56)
  - 1728 Dunciad, Publications
    - AP: Poetry: Names (empty), undated (Box 56)
  - 1729 Dunciad Variorum
    - Pope and the City: London, 1979 (Box 57)
    - Rome, undated (Box 57)
  - Sharrock, undated (Box 58)
  - Health 1731-1735 (empty), 1986 (Box 58)
  - Contemporary Events 1731-1735
    - 1733 Sir John [Checks?] Tomas unto England, 1973 (Box 58)
  - Garden and Grotto 1731-1735, 1979 (Box 58)
  - Publications, 1967-1976 (Box 58)
  - Satires of 1730s
    - AP: Poetry 30's [sociology of AP's poems], 1980 (Box 58)
    - AP: The Person as Problem, 1967 (Box 58)
    - Problems of Formal Satire, undated (Box 58)
  - 1732: Pope-Swift Miscellaneous Publications "Third Volume" (empty), undated (Box 58)
  - 1731: To Burlington, Publications
    - Palladio: Architecture, 1972 (Box 59)
  - 1733: To Bathurst, Publications, 1967 (Box 59)
  - 1733: Essay on Man I-III, Publicatons, 1986 (Box 59)
  - 1733: Imitating Horace's Satire II, i Publications, 1976-1980 (Box 59)
  - 1734: Imitating Horace's Satire II, ii Publications, 1972 (Box 59)
  - 1733: Donne IV: The Impertinent, undated (Box 59)
  - 1733: Letter to a Noble Lord, Publications, 1975 (Box 59)
  - 1734: Imitating Horace's SAT, I ii Publications, 1968 (Box 59)
  - 1734: To Cobham, Publications, 1988 (Box 60)
  - 1734: Essay on Man, IV, Publications, 1980 (Box 60)
  - 1735: To Arbuthnot, Publications, 1970-1982 (Box 60)
  - 1735: Works II, Publications
    - Pope MSS: the 1735-1780 Proofs, undated (Box 60)
  - 1735: Letters, Publications, 1939-1980 (Box 60)
  - 1736-1740 [empty], undated (Box 60)
  - Health 1736-1740, undated (Box 60)
  - Enemies 1736-1740 [enemies], undated (Box 60)
  - House 1736-1740 [empty], undated (Box 60)
  - Garden and Grotto 1736-70, 1965 (Box 60)
  - Publications (Box 60)
  - 1736: Small 80 Works: Publications [empty], undated (Box 60)
  - 1737: Quarto Letters, Publications, 1950 (Box 60)
  - 1737: Imitating Horace's Ep. II, ii Publications [empty], undated (Box 60)
  - 1737: Imitating Hor. Ode IV, i, Publications, 1977 (Box 60)
  - 1738: Imitating Hor. Ep. I, vi Publications [empty], undated (Box 60)
  - 1737: Imit. Hor. EP. II,i, Publications [empty], undated (Box 60)
  - 1738: Epilogue I-II, Publications
    - 1738: Dial 1 and 2, 1960 (Box 60)
    - Untitled folder, undated (Box 60)
  - 1738: Imitating Horace. Ep. I, i Publications, undated (Box 60)
  - 1740-1744, undated (Box 60)
  - Health 1740-1744, undated (Box 60)
  - Enemies 1740-1744 [empty], undated (Box 60)
  - Contemporary Events 1736-1740 and Amica 1741-1744, 1944-1983 (Box 61)
  - Lyttelton Papers
    - Lyttelton Correspondence, undated (Box 61)
    - Starr Papers, undated (Box 61)
  - House 1740-1744 [empty], undated (Box 61)
  - Publications
    - Brutus, undated (Box 61)
  - Memoirs of Scriblerus, undated (Box 61)
  - Death 1740-1744
    - Pope: Possessions, 1950-1959 (Box 62)
    - "Amica", 1989 (Box 62)
    - Pope: His Will, undated (Box 62)
    - AP: Death, 1980 (Box 62)
  - Criticism General: 1740-1800
    - AP: General Criticism 1744-1800, undated (Box 62)
  - Criticism General: 1800-1900 (Box 62)
  - Criticism General: 1900--
    - AP: General Criticism 1900--, 1988 (Box 62)
    - Bibliography of Pope Criticism, 1960 (Box 62)
    - Literature and Society, 1956 (Box 62)
    - Metaphysical, Augustan, Romantic, undated (Box 62)
    - Augustan Poetic Style: Devices, undated (Box 62)
    - P as F: Art of Satire, undated (Box 62)
    - Book on Augustan Idiom 1600-1750, undated (Box 62)
    - P as F: Augustan Imagery and Modes, undated (Box 62)
    - Rochester Lecture, undated (Box 63)
    - Key Metaphors, Etc., undated (Box 63)
    - Pope: Phrases About, undated (Box 63)
    - Pope: Adjectives, undated (Box 63)
    - Pope Mythography, undated (Box 63)
  - Garden and City Reference Material, 1959 (Box 63)
  - Garden and City Materials
    - Garden and City Permissions, 1968 (Box 63)
    - Correspondence Concerning Garden and City Plates, 1962-1970 (Box 63)
    - Garden and City: Reviews, 1970 (Box 63)
    - Garden and City Second Edition, 1982 (Box 63)
    - Pope: Garden: General, 1967 (Box 64)
    - Pope: Grotto: General, 1966 (Box 64)
  - Houses
    - Binfield House, [Chewich?] House, undated (Box 64)
    - Pope: Villa: General, 1977-1989 (Box 64)
    - Pope: Villa: Farington, undated (Box 64)
    - Pope: Villa: Plans and Influences, undated (Box 64)
    - Pope: Villa: Heckell, 1978 (Box 64)
    - Pope: Villa: Newcastle Magazine, undated (Box 64)
    - Pope: Villa: Scott, undated (Box 64)
    - Pope: Villa: Nickolls, undated (Box 64)
    - Pope: Villa: Rysbrack, undated (Box 64)
    - Twickenham: Ironsides, undated (Box 64)
    - Twickenham and Richmond: Views, undated (Box 64)
    - Twickenham: Engravings: Walker Article, 1968 (Box 64)
    - Duncombe Park, 1968 (Box 64)
    - Ham House, 1968 (Box 64)
    - Stanton Harcourt, undated (Box 64)
    - Houghton, undated (Box 64)
    - Stourhead, undated (Box 64)
  - Pope: Iconography: Richardson, 1966 (Box 64)
  - Pope: Iconography: Rysbrack, undated (Box 64)
  - Pope: Countess of Burlington, undated (Box 64)
  - Pope: Iconography: Dahl, undated (Box 64)
  - Pope: Iconography: General, 1987-1971 (Box 64)
  - Pope: Iconography: Hoare, 1964-1968 (Box 65)
  - Pope: Iconography: Jervas, undated (Box 65)
  - Pope: Iconography: Kneller, undated (Box 65)
  - Pope: Iconography: Political Engravings, undated (Box 65)
  - Pope: Iconography: Roubiliac, 1974 (Box 65)
  - Rysbrack Bust, 1985 (Box 65)
  - Political Engravings: General, undated (Box 65)
  - Pope: Iconography: Satirical Engravings, 1960 (Box 65)
  - General, undated (Box 65)
  - Caricature Group by John Hamilton Mortimer, undated (Box 65)
  - Pope: as Painter, 1975 (Box 65)
  - Pope's MSS [empty], undated (Box 65)
  - Pope MSS: Permissions, 1977-1980 (Box 65)
  - Pastorals, 1980 (Box 65)
  - Sappho to Phaon, undated (Box 65)
  - Preface to Works 1717, undated (Box 65)
  - Essay on Man, undated (Box 65)
  - Eloisa MSS., undated (Box 65)
  - Minor MSS: Boethius, Brutus, Grotto at Crux E., Letters of Pope to Trumbull, The Worms, AP Lines Imitating I Said to My Heart, undated (Box 66)
  - J. Richardson's Collations: 1) 1717 Volume; 2) Dunciad, undated (Box 66)
  - Original Sheets: Transcript Notes, undated (Box 66)
  - Pope MSS Volume: Introductions, undated (Box 66)
  - Burlington ME IV 1731, undated (Box 66)
  - ME IV Burlington, 1976 (Box 66)
  - Chatsworth MS (Wragge thought by Pope), undated (Box 66)
  - J. Richardson's Collations: Dunciad 1728, 1736, undated (Box 66)
  - Epistle to Jervas, 1972 (Box 66)
  - Pope MSS: MLA, Fragments of Roxburghe Introduction, undated (Box 66)
  - Balaam, South Sea, Etc., undated (Box 66)
  - Epistle to Addison, undated (Box 66)
  - Photocopies of Pope manuscript and M.M.'s notes, undated (Box 67)
  - AP MSS: Essay on Man
    - Essay on Man, undated (Box 67)
    - Essay on Man: Roxburghe, undated (Box 67)
  - Arbuthnot, 1967 (Box 67)
  - Epistle to Arbuthnot, undated (Box 67)
  - Satire II, i, 1977 (Box 68)
  - Satire II, i, 1966 (Box 68)
  - Satire II, i [empty], undated (Box 68)
  - Brutus, undated (Box 68)